Arshad Habib

Email: arshadmhabib@gmail.com CAREER OBJECTIVE

Rising college senior with 2+ years of work experience aiming to leverage proven knowledge of advanced technology, web, and application development skills to successfully fill the IT Project Management, Security and Software Engineering intern role.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN-MADISON- Madison, WI (2017 - Present) Cumulative GPA: 3.45

Major: B.S. Computer Science (Honors) (Expected graduation June 2021) Certificate (minor): Business

• Relevant Courses:

- Java: Data Structures, Computer Engineering (ISA, Microprocessor, Logic gates), Human-Computer Interaction, Discrete Mathematics, Machine Organization & Programming, Cryptography, Web Design
- Business courses: Human Resources Management, Microeconomics, Financial Accounting, Finance

• Clubs and Organizations: MSA Logistics and Marketing Chair, AI Club, Honors College, Helping Hand Volunteer SKILLS

- Computer Languages: Object-Oriented: Java, Python, HTML, CSS, C, C++, Javascript, R, SQL
- Tools: Unix / Linux, JSON, Java FX (GUI), SSH (shell scripting), Git, Computer Networks, Firewall, Antivirus
- **Data Structures:** Understanding time-complexity and implementations of Trees (Binary, Red Black, AVL, etc), Queue, Hash Table, List (ArrayList, LinkedList).
- **Accumulated** debugging and testing experience with Test Driven Development and White Box testing using JUnit and traditional testing methods.
- **Developed** knowledge in troubleshooting problems on Windows System versions 7, 8 and 10, macOS, and iOS.
- **Proficient** experience in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint), Creative Cloud applications (Photoshop) and Web design platforms such as Weebly, Wordpress, and Wix.
- **Languages:** Arabic (4th semester) highly proficient, Tamil (Native Language) conversational, Spanish (intermediate), English (Advanced writing, reading and spoken)

WORK EXPERIENCE

ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION MANAGEMENT SERVICES @ UW-MADISON, Madison, WI

Computer Systems Technician, Mar 2018 - August 2019

- Accelerated the deployment service of hardware and software to customers in compliance with the AIMS routine of package
 installation, customization, configuration and advocated effective and satisfactory solutions to enhance company reputation.
- Allocated users into domains and groups in the active directory to manage and secure network resources.
- Outlined the core tasks at team meetings which improved task completion and efficiency by 20%.
- Educated my colleagues with AIMS procedure and gained leadership experience in the administration resulting in better work effectiveness spurred by a reduction in migration time by 10%.

SUMMER INTERNSHIP @ WORCESTER ISLAMIC CENTER— WORCESTER, MA

IT Management Intern, May 2019 - Aug 2019, Management & Graphic Design Intern, July 2018 - August 2018

- Administered and thoroughly analyzed the Mohid financial database software for using the platform to the organization's advantage through enhancing the communication with customers, creating programs and managing expenses.
- Designed the Standard Operating Procedures for community events, facility use policies and committees.
- Chaired the WIC Magazine project accumulating useful annual updates of the center which enhanced communication and community satisfaction by more than 50% and specialized in graphic design, editorial, and content creation.
- Restructured the hierarchy of the Institution's designated sectors which improved service quality and productivity by 50%.

DIVISION OF INFORMATION-TECHNOLOGY @ UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN-MADISON

DoIT Network Applications VOIP and UC Deployment Technician, July 2017 - Mar 2018

- Deployed the latest Cisco VOIP phones for customers across the university campus to upgrade communication.
- Established positive customer relations by providing satisfactory and meticulous customer service.

WISCONSIN ICECUBE PARTICLE ASTROPHYSICS CENTER INTERNSHIP

Astrophysics Internship - Intern, Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

• Contributed to the data processing with the goal to determine an effective algorithm for the investigation of Neutrino particle occurrences and interactions using the Python language.